Rahul Dixit

LEAD DEVELOPER

Address: Bangalore, India Mobile: +91 7972648660 Email: dixit.rahul94@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rahuldixitblr/

Git: https://github.com/Rahuld27



Summary

As a Senior Software Developer with over 5+ years of experience in the industry, I have developed a diverse range of skills in software development. My primary focus has been on NodeJS, ReactJS, AWS, HTML, CSS, SQS, Amplify, Nginx, MongoDB, GIT, EC2, and Lambda, but I have also worked with other technologies, such as VBA, SQL, C++, Java, JS, Python, C++, SCALA.

Skills

Node.js (5.1 years)
React.js (4.0 years)
AWS (5.1 years)
HTML (5.1 years)

• • • • • **SQL** (5.1 years)
• • • • • **GIT** (5.1 years)

• • • • • JavaScript (4.0 years)

• • • • • **REST** (4.0 years)

Operations (2.3 years)Forecasting (1.1 years)

• • • • • Backend (5.1 years)

• • • • • Agile (1.7 years)• • • • • CSS (5.1 years)

• • • • • Automation (2.3 years)

• • • • • Leadership (2.3 years)

• • • • • Frontend (0.8 years)

• • • • • Python (2.3 years)

• • • • Java (2.3 years)

• • • • • Hadoop (0.7 years)

Docker (0.8 years) Auditing (1.1 years)

• • • • • • Access (1.1 years)

• • • • • Kubernetes (0.8 years)

• • • • • • Infrastructure (0.8 years)
• • • • • Apache/Nginx (0.2 years)

Three.js (0.2 years)

• • • • • AWS Code Deploy (3.3 years)

Experience

ExarFit 01-2023 - Ongoing

Sr Software Developer

- Design and build high-quality systems using React, NodeJS, MongoDB and AWS stack.
- Creating Scalable Backend Infrastructure using NodeJS and Fastify.
- Managing server using Nginx and automating CI/CD using AWS services.
- Working on threeJS to manage 3d models and integrating it with Front End App.
- Define and coach engineering best practices in the team, fostering a culture of quality, pair programming, clean coding, and testdriven development.
- Strengthen the team's agile practices through continuous improvement activities.

Node.js; React.js; AWS; HTML; SQL; GIT; JavaScript; REST; Backend; Agile; CSS; Apache/Nginx; Three.js; AWS Code Deploy;

Datman Itd 04-2022 - 01-2023

Software Engineer II Bengaluru, India

- Working on Payment Gateway backend development and their integration Designing secured systems to manage the payment transactions.
- Building highly scalable web applications using nodeJs and other JS library.
- Front-end Development using AWS Amplify, React JS, HTML, CSS.
- Designing database structure based on the project requirements.
- Deploying using AWS services.

- Managing end to end deployment on different environments and using GIT as version control system Working in agile methodology and adhering to project guidelines and delivery.
- Building reusable code and libraries Create and nurture highly available systems on Kubernetes.
- Contributing to entire application lifecycle using clean code and debugging.
- Developing functional & stable web applications and performing UI/unit tests to optimise performance.
- Ensuring consistency among all environment's wrt frontend and backend deployment's Deploying to and orchestrating containers.
- Create the container infrastructure platform & Improve the monitoring and alert system.
- Experience in combining Docker with monitoring and logging tools

Node.js; React.js; AWS; HTML; SQL; GIT; JavaScript; REST; Backend; Agile; CSS; Frontend; Docker; Kubernetes; Infrastructure; AWS Code Deploy;

Maveric-Systems 08-2021 - 04-2022

Software Engineer I Bengaluru, India

- Build distributed, reliable, and scalable data pipelines to ingest and process data in real-time.
- Designing and coding Hadoop applications to analyse data collections.
- Creating Machine learning models for banking applications Testing scripts and analysing results.
- Checking model accuracy and data integrity based on the regression outputs.
- Deploying trained deep learning, machine learning models inside containers.
- Data processing which includes label encoding, scaling, imputing to ensure model efficiency and adaption.
- Data visualisation and profiling, data analysis and reporting, for big data analytics.

Node.js; React.js; AWS; HTML; SQL; GIT; JavaScript; REST; Backend; Agile; CSS; Hadoop;

Amazon IN 04-2019 - 07-2021

Catalog Specialist I Bengaluru, India

- Designating responsive templates using CSS techniques and JavaScript libraries.
- Execute and schedule html rich campaigns on homepage, category pages and various cross-category pages across the A.in site.
- Identify opportunities for automation (VBA, Java, Python, node JS), and scale winning experiences.
- Bringing mock-ups or wire-frames to life using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Monitoring website performance and rectifying front-end-related issues.
- Using various AWS Tools to optimise and assess the quality of the internal automated tools which requires to run on scale.
- Using Node JS to implement lookalike travelling salesmen problem and optimising the Delivery agents routing experience.
- Allying with vendors and cross-functional teams to fix & improve products and automating tasks through appropriate tools & scripting.
- Documenting development phases & monitoring systems and ensuring software is upto-date with the latest technologies.
- Improving operations by 17% by conducting systems analysis and recommending changes in policies & procedures.
- Always following Amazon leadership principles to provide seamless better customer experience.

Node.js; React.js; AWS; HTML; SQL; GIT; JavaScript; REST; Operations; Backend; CSS; Automation; Leadership; Python; Java; AWS Code Deploy;

Amazon IN 03-2018 - 03-2019

Catalog Assistant Bengaluru, India

- Configured internal class library for the SQL Server database access layer for Amazon Home Services Team.
- Populating and proposing content for the product catalogs on the Amazon websites.
- Discerned for developing excellent test plans/scripts and rapidly discovering defects.
- Assisted to high-reliability technology releases as a result of thorough testing that helped maintain Amazon Home Services leading sales ranking and customer-satisfaction rating i.e. 4.6/5 (Oct 2018).
- Auditing system configuration for PAN India Amazon.in inventory and compute the supply requirement make sure better accuracy on order forecasting KEY DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Node.js; AWS; HTML; SQL; GIT; Forecasting; Backend; CSS; Auditing; Access;

Education

Master degree in Computer Science

Liverpool John Moores University

2022 **Post-Graduation** in Full Stack Development

IIITE

2017 Bachelor degree in Computer Engineering

Savitribai Phule Pune University

Training

2021 Bootcamp - Data Structures and Algorithms, Upgrad

2021 Data Structures and Algorithms - Series I, Upgrad

Languages

Hindi: Native or bilingual

English: Full professional